A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2 FA806
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2
1919-1963
Rockefeller Archive Center
Jacobs, Walter A. (Walter Abraham), 1883-1967
James, Henry, Jr.
Barus, Maxwell
Flexner, Simon
Brown, Wade H.
Pearce, Louise, b. 1886
Norris, James U.
Flinn, Waldo R.
Greene, Jerome D.
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
Cogger, John W.
Rockefeller University
Smith, Edric Brooks
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA806
5 document box(es)
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 212-2
Arrangement note
The Assistant Business Manager records are arranged in multiple series:
Series 2: Correspondence
Series 3: Subject Files
Series 5: Social Service Records
Conditions Governing Access note
Series 2: Limited access. Personnel-related material is restricted.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids
FA013 Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3
FA807 Rockefeller University records, Assistant Business Manager, Social Service records, Personnel, Series 5
Tryparsamide; Patent medicines; Civil defense; Wages -- Accounting; Vivisection; Health insurance; Jacobs, Walter A. (Walter Abraham), 1883-1967; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. War Demonstration Hospital; James, Henry, Jr.; Barus, Maxwell; Flexner, Simon; Brown, Wade H.; Pearce, Louise, b. 1886; Norris, James U.; Flinn, Waldo R.; Greene, Jerome D.; Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975; Cogger, John W.; Rockefeller University; Merck & Co; Smith, Edric Brooks; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Correspondence, 1919-1920, 1922-1963, n.d.; 2; 2.2 Cubic Feet 5 boxes.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged in two subseries:
  1. Waldo Flinn - Tryparsamide Files, 1919-1920, 1922-1946, 1948-1951, 1953.
  2. Waldo Flinn - Detlev W. Bronk Correspondence, 1946-1953.
  Related Archival Materials note
  For material on tryparsamide, See also: FA137 Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Subject Files and FA214 Rockefeller University records, Director of Administrative Services, Roger C. Elliot, Reports: Bursar’s Receipts and Disbursements
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Limited access. Personnel-related material is restricted from scholary access.
  - Waldo Flinn - Tryparsamide Files, 1919-1920, 1922-1946, 1948-1951, 1953; 1; 4 box(es)
    Scope and Contents note
    This subseries includes brochures, correspondence, memoranda, and reports. Correspondents include Maxwell Barus, Wade Brown, Simon Flexner, Walter A. Jacob, and Louise Pearce. Subjects include Merck & Company, patent medicines, and tryparsamide.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    Biographical/Historical note
    Waldo Flinn was assistant business manager of the RIMR from 1927 until 1955 when he assumed the post of business manager.
    - American Medical Association - Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Barus, Maxwell, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Barus, Maxwell, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barus, Maxwell, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barus, Maxwell - re: C. F. Boehringer & Soehne, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Brazil, 1925, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - British Pharmacopoeia Commission, 1929, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - C. F. Boehringer & Soehne, 1929, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - C. F. Boehringer & Soehne, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - C. F. Boehringer & Soehne, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Committee on Revision of the Pharmacopoeia of the United States of America - E. Fullerton (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Costa Rica, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fish, Richardson & Neave, 1923-1925, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Injuries from Tryparsamide, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Leutin - Cuba, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - License Agreements, 1924-1925, 1927-1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Manufacturing Applications Declined, 1924, 1926-1928, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - May & Baker, Ltd., 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Merck & Company, Inc., 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Merck & Company, Inc., 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Merck & Company, Inc., 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Merck & Company, Inc., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Merck & Company, Inc. - Conrey, H. S., 1930-1933, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1924-1926, 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1931-1938, 1940-1942, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Patent Material, 1920, 1922, 1928-1929, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Patent Material, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Patent Material, 1933-1934, 1936, 1940-1941, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Poulenc Freres, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Poulenc Freres, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Poulenc Freres, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Poulenc Freres, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Powers, Weightman, Rosengarten Company, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Powers, Weightman, Rosengarten Company, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Powers, Weightman, Rosengarten Company, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Produits Chimiques et Pharmaceutiques Meurice, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Produits Chimiques et Pharmaceutiques Meurice, January-March 1925 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Produits Chimiques et Pharmaceutiques Meurice, April-December 1925 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Produits Chimiques et Pharmaceutiques Meurice, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Produits Chimiques et Pharmaceutiques Meurice, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Report - "Tryparsamide in Paresis and African Sleeping Sickness," by Wade H. Brown and Louise Pearce (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Sales of Tryparsamide, 1930-1931, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sales of Tryparsamide, 1937-1939, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Societ Parisienne d'Expansion Chimique, 1928-1932 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Societ Parisienne d'Expansion Chimique, 1933-1934, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Synthetic Drug Company, Canada, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Synthetic Drug Company, Canada, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Synthetic Drug Company, Canada, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Synthetic Drug Company, Canada, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Synthetic Drug Company, Canada, 1928-1929, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Tryparsamide - Argentina, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Tryparsamide - Australia, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Tryparsamide - Austria, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Tryparsamide - Belgian Congo, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Tryparsamide - Brazil, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Tryparsamide - Canada, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Tryparsamide - Ceylon, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Tryparsamide - Chile, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Tryparsamide - China, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tryparsamide - Colombia, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Tryparsamide - Costa Rica, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Tryparsamide - Cuba, 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Tryparsamide - Denmark, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Tryparsamide - Ecuador, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Tryparsamide - Germany, 1934-1935, 1937-1938, 1944-1945, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Tryparsamide - Holland, 1919, 1922, 1925-1928, 1931, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tryparsamide - India, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Tryparsamide - Ireland, 1927-1929 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tryparsamide - Italy, 1925-1930, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Tryparsamide - Japan, 1944-1945, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Tryparsamide - Mexico, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Tryparsamide - New Zealand, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tryparsamide - Norway, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Tryparsamide - Peru, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Tryparsamide - Philippines, 1941-1948, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Tryparsamide - Portugal, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Tryparsamide - Processes (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Tryparsamide - Puerto Rico, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Tryparsamide - Registration (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Tryparsamide - Southern Rhodesia, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Tryparsamide - Spain, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Tryparsamide - Spain, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Tryparsamide - Sweden, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Tryparsamide - Switzerland, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tryparsamide - Turkey, 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Tryparsamide - Union of South Africa, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Tryparsamide - United States, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Tryparsamide - "U. S. Pharmacopoeia", 1933-1934, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Tryparsamide - Uruguay, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Tryparsamide - Venezuela, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Tryparsamide Conferences, 1924-1925, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Usines Chimiques des Laboratoires Francais, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Waldo Flinn - Detlev W. Bronk Correspondence, 1943-1953; 2; 1 box(es)
    Arranged chronologically.
    Materials in this subseries consist of memoranda. Subjects include agenda items for the Board of Trustees meetings, 1955 study of animal case costs, the President's residence and social service matters for employees of the Institute.
    - Correspondence - Detlev W. Bronk, 1946-1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Detlev W. Bronk, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - Detlev W. Bronk, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Detlev W. Bronk, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Detlev W. Bronk, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: Board of Trustees Meetings, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: Board of Trustees Meetings, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: Board of Trustees Meetings, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence re: Board of Trustees Meetings, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)